今晚的嘉宾经历非凡
Our guest tonight has a remarkable story.
22岁时  爱丽丝·克拉克
At age 22, Alice Clark
来到了卢旺达的丛林  研究
journeyed to the jungles of Rwanda where she studied
强大的银背大猩猩
the mighty silverback gorilla.
请留言
Please leave a message.
爱丽丝  要开始了
Alice, they're about to begin.
你在哪
Where are you?
当她回到美国时
When she returned to America,
克拉克女士将她对于主导灵长类动物的广泛研究
Ms. Clark applied her extensive research
应用到了都市丛林中的
on dominant primates to the alphas
精英身上
of our urban jungle,
她为几位世界上最杰出的领导人
advising some of the world's most prominent leaders
以及他们的配偶出谋划策
and their spouses,
激发了她最近一本非小说类畅销书的灵感
which inspired her latest nonfiction bestseller,
《交配仪式: 恋爱实战指南》
"Mating Rituals: A Field Guide to Relationships."
请大家欢迎爱丽丝·克拉克
Please welcome Alice Clark.
快接啊
Come on, come on, come on.
你没事吧
You okay?
-没事  只是  -怎么了
- Yeah. I am. Just... - What?
它好像在盯着我
It's like he's glaring at me.
-你什么意思  莱纳斯吗  -是啊
- What? What do you mean? Linus? - Mm-hmm.
每次我来这里  就感觉他在看着我
Whenever I come over here, it feels like he's watching me.
你注意到当你移动时  它依然盯着你吗
Do you ever notice how his eyes follow you when you move?
是啊  我喜欢那样  能让你保持警觉
Yeah. I love that. It keeps you on alert.
卡塞尔
Yeah, well, Castle,
我是名警察  总是保持警觉
I'm a cop. I'm always on alert.
我回家后只想休息
When I come home, I just wanna... relax.
不是盯着一只饥饿的狮子的眼睛入睡
Not fall asleep staring into the eyes of a hungry lion
它好像要扑过来似的
about to pounce.
等等
Wait a minute.
你不是
You're not, uh...
你不是让我扔了莱纳斯吧
You're not asking me to get rid of Linus, are you?
不  我只是在想
No, I was-- I was just thinking
也许你可以把画挂在别的房间里
that maybe you could move it to another room.
别的房间
Another room?
是  比如说
Yeah, like, um...
你的办公室
Maybe your office.
我的办公室
My office?
贝克特  好  我们马上到
Beckett. Yes. Okay. We'll be right there.
有起谋杀案
There's been a murder.
是啊  莱纳斯简直被你伤透了
Yeah, of Linus' feelings.
只不过  我是用《枪林弹雨》的第一次版税
It's just, I bought Linus with my first royalty check
买下莱纳斯的
from "In a Hail of Bullets."
他是我的图腾  狂暴不驯  我的卧室就是兽穴
He's my totem, wild and untamed, and my bedroom is my lair.
我懂  卡塞尔  但是
I know, Castle, but, um,
那现在是我俩的"兽穴"了吧
isn't it kind of our lair now?
但是狮子莱纳斯是我性格的一部分
But Linus the lion is part of my identity.
你不会想要剥夺我的个性吧
You don't wanna strip me of my identity, do you?
不  知道吗
No. You know what?
你说得对  对不起
You're right. I'm sorry.
我可以住在我家
I can just stay at my own place.
谢谢  等等  不  那不...
Thanks. Wait. No. That's not...
莱恩  什么情况
So, Ryan, what do we got?
死者名叫爱丽丝·艾米·克拉克  37岁  胸口有枪伤
Victim is Alice Amy Clark, 37, G.S.W. to the chest.
泊车员一小时前发现了她
Uh, parking attendant found her an hour ago.
显然她是个心理医生
Apparently, she's some kind of therapist,
在这栋大楼里有间办公室
has an office here in the building.
等等  爱丽丝·克拉克
Wait. Alice Clark?
不是那个爱丽丝·克拉克吧
Not the Alice Clark?
和高富帅谈恋爱的专家
Relationship guru to the rich and famous?
《交配仪式: 恋爱实战指南》的作者
Author of "Mating Rituals: A Field Guide to Relationships"?
-你认识她吗  -只知道她名气很大
- You know her? - By reputation only.
她觉得  我们可以通过承认动物本性
She has the idea that, uh, we can improve our relationships
来改善关系
by acknowledging our animal nature.
比如说  保护和培养的本能
Um... the instinct to protect and nurture, for example,
就是说  提供分享自己的"巢穴"
by say, offering to share one's lair.
说到动物本性
Ah, well, speaking of animal nature,
你该看看她车里的情况
you should see the inside of her car.
-天啊  -被划得乱七八糟
- Oh, wow. - It's been completely torn apart.
从血液溅出的情况来看
And from the spatter pattern, it looks like
这一切都是在她被杀后进行的
all of this was done after she was killed.
所以他们杀了她  然后杀了这辆车
So they killed her, then they killed her car.
他们是在找东西
So they were looking for something.
是啊  找的不是她的钱包  电话或者钥匙
Yeah, and it wasn't her wallet, phone, or keys, either.
凶手没拿走那些东西
Killer didn't bother with those
或是我们在她钱包里找到的一万块
or the 10 grand that we found inside her purse.
她随身携带的钱可真多
That's a lot of walking-around money,
即使是对畅销书作者而言
even for a bestselling author.
如果他们要的不是钱
So if they weren't after the money,
那是什么呢
what were they looking for?
知道案发时间了吗
When did this happen?
根据体温和尸斑
Based on body temp and lividity,
我认为是在昨晚六点到八点之间
I'd say between 6:00 and 8:00 last night.
你看了监控录像吗
Did you get a look at security cams?
车库没有监控摄像头
Garage doesn't have camera coverage,
但是大楼的其它地方有
but other parts of the building do.
他们正在为我们调出录像
They're pulling tape for us right now.
有人打电话给她吗
Somebody calling her?
不  是提醒闹钟
No, it's some kind of reminder alarm.
每过几分钟就响一次
Keeps going off every few minutes.
NF1945
"N-F-1-9-4-5."
埃斯波西托和她助理在楼上  他也许知道
Esposito's with her assistant upstairs. He might know.
我一点也不知道这事
I don't know anything about it,
我大概在四点半离开办公室  帮忙布置会场
but I left the office around 4:30 to go help set up.
她没出现时  我就知道出了事
When she didn't show, I knew something was wrong.
你走后她在等谁吗
Was she expecting anyone after you left?
和谁有约吗
Any appointments?
没有  实际上  她让我取消了所有昨天的约会
No. In fact, she had me cancel them all for yesterday.
有原因吗
Any reason?
我想她需要时间来为演讲做准备
I assume she wanted time to prep for the lecture.
她白天大部分时间都在办公室里
She spent most of the day in her office.
她只接过男友马特的电话
Only call she took was from her boyfriend Matt.
她提到过带着什么贵重的东西吗
Did she mention having anything of value on her?
别人可能要找的东西
Something that someone might have been looking for?
没有  为什么这么问
No. Why do you ask?
整个地方被翻了个遍  就像车里一样
The whole place was turned inside out, just like the car.
拿走了什么
And what was taken?
没什么有价值的
Nothing valuable.
电脑  iPad  画作
Computers, iPads, artwork--
显眼的东西都还在
all the obvious stuff was still there.
那他们在找什么
So what were they looking for?
不知道  她的助理说
I don't know. The assistant said
他们翻了客户档案
that they went through her client files.
爱丽丝的客户里不乏一些大人物
Alice counseled some serious V.I.P.S --
总裁  政客  将军
C.E.O.s, politicians, generals,
她每次治疗都存有了详细的记录
and she took very detailed notes of every session.
世界名流最私密的隐私
The most intimate details of the world's elite?
足够作为杀人动机了
People have been killed for a lot less.
丢失什么档案了吗
Are there any files missing?
助理正在整理
Well, the assistant is combing through everything now,
-但得花上点时间  -好了
- but it's gonna take some time. - All right.
我看了大楼的监控录像
So I scrubbed her building security video,
来看这个
and check this out.
这人在死亡时间区的末端
This guy went up to Alice's office floor
上了爱丽丝办公室那层楼
near the tail end of our time-of-death window,
昨晚就他一个人上去过
and he was the only person up there last night.
也就是说只有他
Which means he's the only person
可能翻过爱丽丝的办公室
who could have tossed Alice's place.
看啊  他每次经过摄像头都会转头
Check it out. He's turned away from the camera every shot.
不让我们看到他的脸  就是他
Hiding his face from us. This is our guy.
警探  死者的男朋友来了
Detective? Your victim's boyfriend is here.
没有  从没见过他
No. Never seen him before.
你也不知道他在找什么吗
And you have no idea what he might have been looking for?
都怪我
This is my fault.
我昨晚本该去接她的
I was supposed to pick her up last night,
但我公事缠身
but I got held up at work.
你在哪工作
Where is it that you work, exactly?
我是一个国际援助非政府组织的顾问
I'm a consultant for an international aid N.G.O.
她一直在帮人
All she did was help people.
怎么会有人要杀她
Why would anyone wanna kill her?
你觉得她最近怎么样
How did she seem to you lately?
有没有任何迹象表明
Was there anything to indicate
她最近不太顺利
she was having any troubles in her life?
没有
No, nothing.
她挺开心的
She seemed happy.
那她的客户呢
And how about her clients?
有哪个比较棘手吗
Was she having difficulty with anyone?
有时会有
Sometimes.
她的客户咄咄逼人
Uh, the people she counseled could be aggressive,
十分苛求  但她就喜欢挑战
demanding, but she liked the challenge--
驯服野兽什么的
Taming the wild beast and all that.
有没有特别突出的人
Did anyone stand out in particular?
爱丽丝  对工作闭口不谈
Alice was... discreet about her work.
不过那天午餐
Though at lunch the other day,
她...有点心不在焉
she... seemed a little rattled.
她说接到一个愤怒的客户打来的电话
She said she'd received a call from a pissed-off client.
你知道是谁吗
Do you know who?
正如我所说  她闭口不谈
Like I said, she was discreet.
好吧  谢谢
Okay, thanks.
听听这个
Hey, listen to this.
两个物种的雄性都会明确领地
"Males of both species define their territory,
为表敬意  邀请雌性进入
then honor the female by inviting them in."
看见没  我为表敬意  邀请你进入我的领地
See, I'm--I'm honoring you by inviting you into my territory,
而莱纳斯是那领地的一部分
and Linus is part of that territory.
如果你想再受邀进入我的领地
And if you wanna be invited into my territory again,
你该再好好想想了
you should probably rethink that.
鉴证组刚查过车和办公室
So C.S.U. just finished with the car and the office,
没有指纹  几乎没有残留证据
and they found no prints and almost no trace evidence.
就好像
It's like...
都被人清理过了
both locations have been cleaned.
又清理又避开摄像头  是个职业杀手
That and the cameras? This guy's a pro.
那一个职业杀手为什么要杀害
Okay, so then why would a professional assassin
心理医生呢
Murder a therapist?
因为作为心理医生  她知道
Because as a therapist, she'd be privy to
客户内心最深层最阴暗的秘密
her clients' deepest, darkest secrets--
这些秘密太具爆炸性了
Secrets so explosive,
光是听到就得死
that simply hearing them ensured her demise.
-好吧  什么秘密呢  -核弹发射码
- All right, what kind of secrets? - Well... nuclear launch codes,
月球漫步是假的
that the moon walk was a fake,
罗斯威尔飞碟坠毁事件是真的
that Roswell wasn't,
某人低温冷藏尸体的秘密地点...
secret location of the cryogenically frozen body of--
男朋友没问题
Well, um... boyfriend checks out.
打电话到他办公室  他们证实他昨晚
Called his office. They verified that he was working
都在工作  但爱丽丝还真是
all last night, but Alice definitely
一脚踩进了泥潭里
tumbled down the rabbit hole to shadyland.
她手机上的提醒
That alert on her phone--
NF1945是她租的
N-F-1-9-4-5-- it's a tail number
私人飞机的尾号
of a private jet that she chartered.
她租了私人飞机  去哪
She chartered a private jet? To where?
我联系了泰特波罗机场的机师
Well, I contacted the pilot out of Teterboro.
他说爱丽丝给了他五万块现金
He said Alice paid him 50 grand in cash
让他给飞机加满油等着
to be on standby with a full tank of gas,
目的地未知
destination unknown.
她知道自己有麻烦了
She knew she was in trouble.
已经准备好要消失了
She was getting ready to disappear.
她是名畅销书作者  事业有成
Okay, she's a bestselling author with a flourishing career.
要是有麻烦了  为什么不
If she was in trouble, why didn't she
报警或告诉她男朋友
just call the police or her boyfriend?
为什么要租飞机呢
Why would she charter a jet?
伙计们  有发现
Hey, guys? We got something.
现场排查找到了一个卖报人
Canvass turned up a news vendor
看到嫌疑人离开爱丽丝的大楼
who saw our suspect leave Alice's building
开着一辆蓝色厢式货车离开了
and drive off in a blue van.
他之所以记得这个人
But the reason he remembers our guy
是因为他的车就停在一个女人后面
is because his van was parked behind a woman
那女人因为收到违章停车罚单在咒骂交警
who was cursing out a parking officer for giving her a ticket.
幸运的是  交警的车都装有摄像头
Luckily, traffic enforcement's vehicles are mounted
能拍下停着的车辆
with cameras that snap photos of each parked car.
他们就是这样抓停车不缴费的
It's how they catch meter cheaters.
这辆是被罚车辆
Here's the ticketed car.
这辆就是谋杀嫌疑犯的蓝色厢式货车
And here's your murder suspect's blue van.
注册在曼哈顿猛禽有限公司名下
It's registered to a Manhattan Raptor, inc.
有地址吗
We get an address?
把手举起来
Hands! Show me your hands!
绕到后面去
Go around back.
开门
Open up!
上
Go!
把手举起来
Let me see those hands!
我说了把手举起来
I said show me those hands!
怎么样
Well?
身上和车里都没有身份证明
He didn't have an I.D. on him or in his van,
但查过他的指纹后  我们找到了有趣的匹配记录
But we did find an interesting match on his fingerprints.
他是巴莱特·霍克
That's Barrett Hawke?
巴莱特·霍克  那个传奇的清道夫
Barrett hawke? As in the legendary fixer?
他为纽约权贵们
He's been sweeping the dirt of New York's rich and famous
善后十几年了
under the rug for over a decade.
我没找过他  我只是...听说的
Not my dirt. I just... heard.
我也听说过
I've heard, too.
据说  他会不惜一切代价完成任务
Word is, he does what it takes to get the job done.
他是铜墙铁壁  从来没被攻陷过
He's teflon. Nothing ever sticks.
那是因为他非常小心谨慎
That's because he's careful.
他车内存储器里的资料都被清空了
Every memory drive in his van was wiped clean.
没有任何证据能把他和爱丽丝联系起来
There's nothing to tie him back to Alice.
我不管他有多小心  反正有人雇他杀了爱丽丝
I don't care how careful he is, someone hired him to kill her.
这次他别想脱身了
This time he's not walking away.
抱歉  警长  但我这辈子从没见过这女人
Sorry, detective, but I've never seen this woman before in my life.
即使我的同事亲眼目睹
Even though my colleagues witnessed you
你在车里将她的照片放进了碎纸机
In the back of your van, shredding her photo?
你的同事看错了
Your colleagues were mistaken.
那是个微割机
But that was a micro-cut shredder,
所以很不幸  无论怎样都死无对证了
So unfortunately there's no proof either way.
我们知道她遇害时
We can place you in her office building
你在她位于77大街的办公大楼内
on 77th street at the time of her murder.
如果你不认识她
So if you didn't know Alice Clark,
你去那里做什么
What the hell were you doing there?
我最喜欢的擦鞋师父也在那栋楼里
My favorite shoeshine guy's in that building.
是吗  九楼吗
Right. On the ninth floor?
就在她被翻过办公室的那条走廊
Right down the hall from her ransacked office?
看不清他的脸
Can't really make out his face.
很难判定他是谁
Hard to say who that guy is.
得了吧  探长
Come on, detective.
你到底有什么实质的证据
What do you really have on me, huh?
没有任何证据表明我在她办公室里
There isn't a single piece of evidence I was in her office,
或是证明我与她的被害有关
Or that I was involved in her death.
有指纹吗
Prints?
还是DNA
D.N.A.?
任何证据
Anything?
我猜也是
That's what I thought.
就像她说的...铜墙铁壁
Just like she said... teflon.
要拿下这家伙  唯一的办法是查出雇他的人
The only way to nail this man is to figure out who hired him,
要查这人
And for that,
我们就得弄清巴莱特·霍克要找什么
we need to know what Barrett Hawke was sent to find.
我刚查过了这里的一切
I've been through just about everything...
她的研究笔记  她的书籍文档
Her research notes, her book files,
全都没有被碰过
Everything's intact.
我对比索引  反复查了好几次
I've rechecked it a couple of times against our index files,
只少了一样东西
and there's only one thing missing.
是什么
What's that?
一位客户的档案
A client file.
哪位客户
Which client?
安德鲁和莫妮卡·斯潘瑟
Andrew and Monica Spencer.
安德鲁·斯潘瑟  那位酒店房产大亨
Andrew Spencer...the hotel and real estate tycoon?
会有谁想要他的档案呢
Who would want his file?
事实上  我觉得是安德鲁·斯潘瑟想要它
Actually, I think Andrew Spencer wanted it.
他要自己的档案干什么
Why would he want his own file?
因为...
Because...
这事还没公开
Well, it's not public knowledge yet,
不过斯潘瑟夫妇在协议离婚了
But the Spencers are getting a divorce,
就在上周  斯潘瑟夫人的律师
and last week, Mrs. Spencer's attorney
传唤爱丽丝  要求将她所有的诊疗记录
subpoenaed Alice to turn all of her session notes
呈交给法庭
over to the court.
安德鲁·斯潘瑟身家数十亿
Andrew Spencer's worth billions.
如果记录中有对他不利的信息
If there was any compromising information in those notes,
会让他付出相当可观的分手费
It would cost him boatloads in a settlement.
等等  州法律不是规定
Wait. Doesn't, uh, state law protect
心理医生要保护客户的隐私吗
therapist/client privacy?
可爱丽丝并非是有正规执照的心理医生
Except Alice wasn't a licensed therapist.
她更像是个感情导师
She was more of a relationship coach.
当斯潘瑟先生得知
When Mr. Spencer found out
诊疗并不受医患保密协议保护
the sessions weren't privileged...
他非常生气
He hit the roof.
他威胁要告上法庭
He threatened to sue.
看来他不只是要告上法庭啊
Well, looks like he did more than just sue.
你知道在哪能找到他吗
You know where we can find him?
-斯潘瑟先生稍后就来  -好的
- Mr. Spencer will be right with you.  - Okay.
我不得不佩服这个爱丽丝啊  哥们儿
I gotta hand it to this Alice chick, bro.
不管她的猴子理论是什么
Whatever her monkey theory is
还真让她在大人物中混得很开啊
has her in with the movers and the shakers.
她是从真正的大猩猩那学来的
She learned from the real gorillas.
就像是在人类世界中跟360公斤的人合作
Seems to be working with the 800-pound ones in the human world.
她就像总裁们的狗语者一样
She was like the dog whisperer for C.E.O.s
你真相信这些
You really buy that?
嗯  我浏览了一下她的书
Uh, yeah. Skimmed through her book.
我觉得她的理论有些道理
I think there might be something to her theory.
比如  她说在每段感情中
For instance, she said that in every relationship,
都必须有一种男性能量
there needs to be a masculine energy
和一种女性能量  即便我跟你也一样
and a feminine energy, even in ours.
反正我们都知道你是哪种力量
Oh. Well, we know which one you are.
我不知道你怎么想
I don't know about you,
不过我对自己的男性力量挺自信的
But I'm very comfortable in my masculinity.
你知道你穿了件毛背心吧
You do realize you're wearing a sweater vest, right?
这最好是什么重要的事
Better be important.
我刚挂断了新加坡投资集团的电话
I just hung up on my investment group in Singapore.
安德鲁·斯潘瑟  我是埃斯波西托警探
Andrew Spencer, detective Esposito...
我他妈才不在乎你们是谁  你们想干嘛
I don't give a rat's ass who you are. What do you want?
爱丽丝·克拉克  你知道她吗
Alice Clark. You know her?
知道  怎么了
Yeah, I know her. Why?
她有一份客户档案
Well, she had a client file
是你和即将成为你前妻的莫妮卡的
Of you and your soon-to-be ex-wife Monica...
这份档案现在丢失了
A file that's currently missing.
我懂了
Oh, I get it.
是我老婆的律师让你们来的吗
Did my wife's attorney put you up to this?
你们知道这是什么行为吗
You know what this is?
-这是骚扰  -不  斯潘瑟先生
- This is harassment.  - No, mr. Spencer.
这是一次凶案调查
This is a murder investigation.
凶案调查  谁死了
A murder investigation? But who's dead?
爱丽丝
Alice.
她死了
Alice is dead?
得了吧  斯潘瑟
Oh, come on, Spencer.
别装了  我们知道你雇了巴莱特·霍克
Drop the act. We know you hired Barrett Hawke...
去杀她并拿走那份档案
to kill her and take the files.
我们已将他和谋杀联系起来了
We've already linked him to her murder.
不  等等  那和我没关系
No. Wait, wait, wait, wait. That had nothing to do with me.
听着  我是听说过霍克
Look, I've heard of Hawke,
可我从没雇佣过他
but I've never used his services.
我甚至不知道怎么联系他  没错
Hell, I wouldn't even know how to find the guy, and, yes,
我是想要自己的档案  可爱丽丝给我了
I wanted my file, but Alice gave it to me.
她自己送给我的
She brought it to me herself.
我有目击证人
I-I have witnesses.
爱丽丝为什么要给你
Why would Alice give it to you?
我提醒我太太那些心理咨询记录
I reminded my wife that those sessions
含有大量
contained plenty of statements
她也不想交给政府机构备案的内容
that she wouldn't want on the public record either.
她同意我的观点  我们就都联系了爱丽丝
She agreed, and we both called Alice.
爱丽丝理解我们需要保留隐私
Alice understood our need for privacy,
所以她主动交给我们  用来换取我们的帮忙
so she offered to turn it over in exchange for a favor.
是吗  帮什么忙
Yeah? What kind of favor?
说来奇怪
Uh, it's actually strange.
她想要在我的宾馆要间房间
She said she needed a room in one of my hotels
住上几天
for a couple days,
我必须保证没有记录显示
and I had to promise that there'd be no record
她住在那里
that she was ever there.
爱丽丝破费五万包了辆飞机
Alice dropped 50 grand to charter a plane,
还需要斯潘瑟给她安排个房间
yet she needed Spencer to comp a hotel room for her?
那是因为和金钱无关
That's because it wasn't about the money.
重要的是隐姓埋名
It was about the anonymity.
她还告诉前台  她不想要
She even told the front desk that she didn't want
客房服务
housekeeping in her room,
她也没把行踪告诉她男友
and she didn't tell her boyfriend where she was.
她并不需要客房服务
Not that she would need housekeeping.
这里没有行李  浴室里什么都没有
There's no luggage here, nothing in the bathroom.
好像她从没来过这里
It's like she was never even here.
可她昨天上午登记入住了
Yeah, but she checked in yesterday morning.
卡塞尔
Castle?
这里说不定是安全屋呢
What if this was a safe house?
说不定她知道霍克会来找她
What if she knew that Hawke was coming after her?
然后她决定藏在这里
And she decided to hide out here
直到她能逃到境外
until she could flee the country.
让飞机待命  她在等什么
With a plane standing by? What was she waiting for?
不不不  这里一定有蹊跷
No, no, no, no. Something is going on here.
她要这间房间是因为
The reason why she got this room--
她不想让任何人知道
She didn't want anybody to know about it.
保险箱上锁了
The safe is locked.
她用它来藏东西  来看看
She got it to hide something. Come take a look.
我打赌不管霍克找的是什么  都在这里面
I bet whatever Hawke was after, it's in there--
她知道这里会安全
A place she knew it'd be safe,
也知道没人会想到要找它
and knew no one would think to look for it.
所以说东西还在里面
Which means it's still in there.
有没有置换码
Is there an override code?
她就是因为里面藏的东西被杀的
Whatever's in there is the reason why she was killed.
谢谢
Thank you.
卡塞尔  这一定值好几百万
Castle, this must be worth millions.
好几千万呢
Tens of millions.
看来钻石的确是女孩最好的朋友
Looks like diamonds were our girl's best friend.
我还从没在博物馆以外的地方见过这样的钻石
I've never seen anything like this outside of a museum.
你确定这是真品吗
Are you sure it's real?
我们在回来的路上
We stopped at a jewelers
去了家珠宝店  珠宝匠激动得快发心脏病了
on the way back, and he almost had a heart attack.
这一定就是霍克在找的  可...
It has to be what Hawke was after, but...
爱丽丝拿它做什么呢
What was Alice doing with it?
考虑到现金  宾馆房间和私人飞机
Given the cash, the hotel room, and the private plane,
我觉得她在设法逃走
I'd say she was making a getaway.
你是说这是她偷的
Are you saying she stole it?
一个受名流客户青睐的心理医生
A trusted therapist to "A"-list clientele--
打入内部是再容易不过的了
She was in the perfect position to work her way inside.
她是《十一罗汉》  减去十个
She's "Ocean's Eleven," minus ten.
她是《独行罗汉》
She's... "Ocean's One."
或者是《没有罗汉》
Or maybe it's "Ocean's None."
我是说  爱丽丝事业有成
I mean, Alice was successful.
受人尊敬  在业内首屈一指
Well, she's respected. She's at the top of her game.
她何必冒着生命危险偷钻石呢
Why would she risk it all by stealing a diamond?
这又产生了另一个问题
Which brings up another problem.
我问了劫案组和联调局
I spoke to the boys in robbery and at the F.B.I.
没人报告这样的钻石失窃
No one has reported a diamond like this stolen,
不只是最近没有  从来没有
not just recently. Ever.
-那这是哪里来的  -如果这是偷来的
- Then where did it come from? - And if it was stolen,
为什么失主没有报案
why haven't the owners reported it?
说不定是因为失主不能报案
What if it's because they couldn't afford to?
因为这钻石来历不明
Because the diamond has some kind of sordid past.
或许像是希望之星  受了诅咒
Perhaps it's like the Hope Diamond. It's cursed.
又或许这是颗充满强大能量的魔力宝石
Or maybe it's a-- an occult gem of great power,
在纳粹德国时期被偷运出去
smuggled out of Nazi Germany,
-被...  -谢谢  卡塞尔先生
- shoved up some... - Thank you, Mr. Castle.
有人知道它的来历
Someone knows where it came from.
有人派巴莱特·霍克找爱丽丝得到它
Someone sent Barrett Hawke after Alice to get it.
或许这颗钻石能告诉我们
Maybe the diamond could tell us.
什么意思
What do you mean?
你自己也说了
Well, you said it yourself.
你从没在博物馆以外见过这样的钻石
You've never seen anything like this outside of a museum.
这么大的钻石是有名气的  他们有名字
Diamonds this big are famous. They have names--
阿克巴沙赫  阿格拉之星
The Akbar Shah, the Angola star,
艾克沙修
the, um... Excelsior.
这颗钻石也一定有故事
Now this diamond has a story.
如果我们能查明它的故事
If we can figure out what that story is,
它可能会指引我们找到凶手
it might just give us a path to our killer.
对  卡塞尔说得对
Yeah, Castle's right.
纽约是美国钻石交易的中心
This city is the hub of the nation's diamond trade.
这里一定有专家
There has to be an expert out there
能告诉我们这颗钻石的来历
that can tell us where it came from.
尤物
Such beauty.
太耀眼了
It's absolutely stunning.
能说出它的来历吗
Can you tell where it came from?
钻石不是人  警探
Diamonds are not people, detective.
在亚洲开采的钻石
A diamond mined in Asia looks the same
和非洲开采的钻石一个样
as a diamond mined in Africa.
但是  美国没有矿山
However, there are no mines in America,
所以不是美国开采的
so, uh, it is not from here.
我搭档的意思是
Uh, what my partner means is
你以前见过这颗钻石吗
have you come across this stone before?
从没见过
Ah. Never.
作为美国宝石基金会的主席
And as head of the American gemological foundation,
我知道地球上每颗特别的宝石
I know every extraordinary stone on the planet.
-那你不知道钻石的主人是谁  -不知道  我应该知道的
- So you don't know who owns it? - No, and I should.
我是说  发现一块
I mean, a discovery
这样不可思议的宝石是要上头条的
of an incredible gem like this is headline-making.
应该很出名才对
They become famous.
-可能是最近进口的吗  -不
- Uh, could it be a recent import? - No.
我看过所有经过海关的宝石报告
I'm copied on gem reports that pass through customs,
在我在美国珠宝基金会的这些年里
and nothing remotely this size has come through
从来没有这种尺寸的宝石
in my entire tenure at the A.G.F.
这块石头的来源完全是个谜
No, the origins of this stone are a complete mystery.
你们能告诉我你们是怎么得到它的吗
Can you tell me how you came to possess it?
这是一项正在进行中的调查的证物
It's evidence in an ongoing investigation, so...
关于它你能告诉我们什么
What can you tell us about this diamond?
我可以做一些额外的光谱分析
Well, I should like to run additional spectrometer
和成像测试  但是
and imaging tests on it, but, uh,
与此同时  让我从4C测试开始
for the meantime, let me start with the four C's.
颜色  切割  透明度  克拉数
Uh, color, cut, clarity, carat.
如果你买过订婚戒指你会知道的
You'd know this if you ever bought an engagement ring.
这颗钻石是无色的
The diamond is colorless.
没有瑕疵  切割手法很质朴
No blemishes, so a pristine cut,
内部无混浊  而且...
No internal clouding, and, uh...
将近100克拉
nearly 100 carats.
天呐
Man.
想要买得起那样一块钻石
Hey, how deep would my pockets have to be
我得有多少钱
to afford a rock like that?
警探  那些钱摞起来
Detective, you are not tall enough
比你还要高
to have pockets deep enough.
但...  我会说它值...
But... I would say it's worth...
6000万美元
$60 million.
保守估计
Conservatively.
对  我没那么高
Yeah, I ain't that tall.
六个零  后面还要再加六个零
Six-zero? Like with another six zeroes after that?
6000万美元  对
That would be $60 million, yes.
它有没有可能
Is it possible
是世代相传的传家宝
it's an heirloom passed down through generations,
所以才没有关于它的记录
and that's why there's no record of it?
彼得斯说老派的钻石切割者
Nah, Peters said that old-school cutters
喜欢给钻石切出锋利的边缘
fashioned diamonds with sharp edges.
这颗钻石边缘光滑  意味着它是在
This one has smooth edges, which means it had to be cut
近几十年里被切割的
within the last few decades.
没有海关文件说明
No customs declaration means
它是从它被开采出的国家走私来的
it was smuggled in probably from the country where it was mined.
我们能把爱丽丝的哪个客户和钻石
Were we able to connect any of Alice's clients
联系起来吗
to the diamond?
我们还在查  但是目前没有
We're still going through them, but no, not yet.
彼得斯说他还在那颗钻石上
Peters said he also found
发现了一些残胶
some glue residue on the stone,
说明它曾经被装在一件首饰上
which suggests that it was set in a piece of jewelry.
为了广大的已经订婚的男人
For engaged men everywhere,
我只能祈祷不是装在戒指上
I can only hope it wasn't the ring.
把钻石带回局里来
Get that rock back to the precinct.
我需要它被妥善保管并且重兵把守
I want it under lock, key, and armed guard.
我们马上就到
We're on our way.
那么...
So...
我们是在想同一件事吗
Are we thinking the same thing?
我们没法停下来吃午餐
That it's a bummer we can't stop for lunch
因为我们拿着一颗价值6000万的钻石
because there's a $60 million diamond sitting between us?
不  因为我们有一块价值6000万的钻石
No, that because of the $60 million diamond sitting between us,
不是真心  但有些动心
that we are not-really- but-kinda-sorta
带着它远走高飞
thinking about making a run for the border.
我根本就没这么想过
That didn't even cross my mind.
那是当然
Of course it didn't.
不  你不会得到钻石的
Nope. You wouldn't have the stones.
我就是说说而已
All I'm saying.
-你还活着吗  -暂时还活着
- You breathing? - Yeah, for now.
枪  把头低下
Gun! Get down!
他们有三个人  那颗钻石
Three of them! The diamond.
地铁站入口  七点钟方向  我掩护  快走
Subway entrance, 7:00. I'll cover you. Go!
快走
Go!
-你没事吧  -没事
- You all right? - Yeah.
我没事  我...
I'm good. I'm...
你们一到地铁站那辆SUV就开走了
The S.U.V. took off right after you hit the subway.
我们调出了交通监控  而且我们让
We're pulling traffic footage, and we've got
城里的每个警察都去找那辆车
every cop in the city looking for it.
你们说他们戴着面具
And you said they were wearing masks?
对  小丑面具
Yeah, clown masks.
就好像小丑不够吓人似的
As if clowns weren't creepy enough.
那他们的声音呢  他们说什么了吗
What about their voices? Did they say anything?
他们有口音吗
Did they have accents?
出声的只有他们的子弹
Uh, they let their bullets do the talking.
警监  他们光天化日之下袭击了我们
Captain, they attacked us in broad daylight,
而且他们知道钻石在我们手里
and they knew we had the rock.
要么是巴莱特·霍克突然变换了战术
Now either Barrett Hawke has gone commando all of a sudden,
-要么就是还有别的情况  -他说得对
- or something else is going on here. - He's right.
这件事开始变得比一颗钻石
I mean, this is starting to sound like
要复杂得多
it's about a whole lot more than just a diamond.
好吧  去清理干净
Okay. Get cleaned up.
我需要你们俩去找那辆SUV
I need you two to go hunting for that S.U.V.
不管发生了什么  爱丽丝都深陷其中
Whatever's going on, Alice was in it up to her eyeballs.
如果她的客户们跟出产钻石的国家
If any of her clients have even the remotest connection
有任何一点点联系
to a country that produces diamonds,
都必须让我知道
I wanna know about it.
-是  长官  -好吧
- Yes, Sir. - All right.
我在想...
So I was thinking...
当我们在一起工作时
When we work a case together,
你的这张桌子也可以
this desk of yours is sort of
算是我们的空间  而且...
kind of our space, and...
这些大象从第一天开始就让我
These elephants on parade have creeped me out
很不自在  所以如果我们把它们扔了
since day one, so what do you say
你觉得怎么样
we just get rid of these?
抱歉  你有什么意见吗
Oh, I'm sorry. Do you have a problem with that?
如果我试图把
If I try to get rid of something
对你很有意义的东西随手扔掉
that obviously has deep meaning to you?
如果你不喜欢它们  我也不喜欢它们
If you don't like the elephants, I don't like the elephants.
好吧
Fine.
我其实挺喜欢这些大象的
I actually like those elephants.
它们显然有家庭观念
They've obviously have family values,
而且这头对钱很在行
and this one's good with money.
总之...
Anyway...
爱丽丝的客户有线索吗
Any luck on Alice's clients?
有那么几个
Yeah, a couple of possibilities--
一个在南非有投资的
a hedge fund manager
对冲基金经理
with investments in South Africa,
一位与俄国有关的联合国外交官
a U.N. Diplomat with ties to Russia,
一家距中国矿井80英里的制造厂的
and a C.E.O. with a manufacturing plant
首席执行官
80 miles from a chinese mine.
或许我们找错了方向
What if we're looking at this wrong?
或许问题的关键不是爱丽丝的客户
What if it's not about Alice's clients,
而是爱丽丝本身
but it's actually about Alice?
-你的意思是  -当她在非洲
- What do you mean? - When she was living
与大猩猩一起生活时  她就在卢旺达
with the gorillas in Africa, that was in Rwanda,
正好毗邻刚果
right along the border of the Congo--
这一以冲突钻石闻名的国家
A region known for conflict diamonds.
你认为她卷入了血钻交易吗
So you think she was involved in the blood diamond trade?
我想这事已经不言自明了
I think it's a story that writes itself.
一位年轻的灵长类动物学家
A young primatologist
在一片不稳定地区爱上了
In an unstable region falls for
另一种大猩猩  一名军阀
a different kind of gorilla--a warlord
用血钻来筹集军资
who is funding his bloody agenda with diamonds.
他送给她一颗作为礼物
He gives her one as a gift.
不不  倒回去
No. No, go back.
她没那么爱他  钻石是她偷来的
She's not that into him, and she steals the diamond,
却不知道它的真正价值
having no idea its real value.
她把它偷运回美国  却发现
She smuggles it back to the United States and finds
无法无声无息地把它出手
she can't sell it without attracting too much attention,
所以她把它藏了起来  直到有一天
so she hides it until one day
一名被甩而又博览群书的军阀
A jilted and well-read warlord finds a book
在一本书的背面看到了她的照片
and sees her photo on the back.
意识到她偷了自己的钻石
Knowing what she stole,
他来找她了
he comes after her.
这还  真像那么回事
That is... surprisingly plausible.
我也觉得  对吧  这实际上
I know, right? It's actually...
这实际上解释了很多事
That would actually explain a lot--
为什么她要计划消失
Why she was planning to disappear,
为什么埃斯波西托和莱恩
why Esposito and Ryan
会在光天化日之下被枪击
were shot at in broad daylight.
这还真是个完美的猜想
That's actually a perfect theory.
也许吧  卡塞尔  但你知道吗
Maybe, Castle, but you know what?
我也许有个更好的
I might have... a better one.
关于史蒂夫·沃纳你了解多少
What do you know about Steve Warner?
-科技企业家  -没错  显而易见的
- Uh, tech entrepreneur? -Yeah. Apparently,
他和他的妻子是爱丽丝的客户
he and his wife were Alice's clients.
然后呢  他们与钻石生产国
And what, they had business contacts
-有商业关系吗  -没有
- in diamond-producing countries? - No.
但他们的慈善基金有
But their charitable foundation does--
主要是在非洲
Primarily in Africa,
向发展中和饱受战火荼毒的国家运送疫苗
delivering immunizations to developing and war-torn countries.
但你的大慈大悲慈善家故事
Okay. But what makes your heroic philanthropist story
哪里比我的疯狂军阀故事更好呢
better than my crazed warlord story?
这个
This.
这是沃纳夫妇
That's Steve and Janet Warner
两个月前在国际特赦组织义卖上拍摄的
at the amnesty global benefit two nights ago.
珍妮特是他们的董事会成员
Janet's on their board.
-认出什么没有  -你好啊  尤物
- You recognize anything? - Hello, gorgeous.
沃纳先生以及夫人
Mr. And mrs. Warner,
-非常感谢你们能来  -没什么
- Thank you so much for coming. - Of course.
当得知她的死讯时  我们都震惊无比
We can't tell you how shocked we were to hear about Alice.
你们成为她的客户多久了
How long had the two of you been her clients?
有几年了
A couple of years.
她挽救了我们的婚姻
She saved our marriage.
做一对成功人士夫妻很不容易
Being a power couple isn't easy.
爱丽丝理解这一点
Alice understood that.
只是好奇  两位与爱丽丝见面时
Just curious--when the two of you would meet with Alice,
你们去她办公室  还是她来你们家
would you go to her office, or would she come to your home?
都有  为什么这么问
Both. Why?
她能自由出入你们家吗
Did she ever have access to your place?
你们给过她钥匙或安全密码吗
Did you ever give her keys or security codes?
没有  我们怎么会  为什么这么问
No. Why would we? What's this all about?
我们相信她被谋杀与一起盗窃案有关
We believe her murder is connected to a theft.
一起盗窃案
A theft?
是的  一起很重大的盗窃案
Yeah, a rather significant one.
你们有人发觉丢了什么吗
Either of you notice anything missing?
比如
Like what?
对不起  我不明白
I'm sorry. I don't understand.
沃纳先生  这是你的钻石
Mr. Warner, that is your diamond,
100克拉的钻石
All 100 carats of it.
它被发现由爱丽丝持有
It was found in Alice's possession.
知道她怎么拿到的吗
Any idea how she got it?
我想你们搞错了  这不是我们的
I think there's been a mistake. This isn't ours.
-不是吗  -我从未见过这块钻石
- It's not? - I've never that stone before in my life.
真的吗
Really? Well...
那天晚上你戴着它
You were wearing it the other night.
我知道怎么回事了
Oh. I see the confusion.
我脖子上这块不是钻石
The stone in my necklace-- that's not a diamond.
那是礼服的一部分 只是水晶
It's a costume piece. It's just crystal.
水晶  沃纳夫人
Crystal. Mrs. Warner,
这就是那块钻石
that is the same stone.
探长  你搞错了
Detective, you're mistaken.
它们只是看上去相似
They only look similar.
我想你不会介意
Well, then I suppose you won't mind
我们派警探
if we send one of our detectives
和你一同回家看看吧  只是确认下
Home with you to look at it? Just to be sure.
我想我们没什么好说的了
I think we're done here.
如果还有问题
If you have any more questions,
直接跟我律师谈吧
you can direct them to my attorneys.
他们显然在撒谎
Of course they're lying,
但问题是他们为什么要撒谎
but the real question is why are they lying?
鉴于他们的身家
Well, given their net worth,
损失6000万美元
better to take a $60-million loss
比跟一具死尸扯上关系好
than be connected with a dead body.
不  卡塞尔  没这么简单
No, Castle, it's more than that.
如果他们知道爱丽丝偷了钻石
If they knew that Alice stole that diamond,
他们会报警  但他们没有
they should've gone to the cops, but they didn't.
为什么
Why?
因为一旦他们报警  就不得不
Probably because if they did, that would mean
说明钻石是哪来的
having to reveal where the diamond came from.
没人听说过它一定是有原因的
There's gotta be a reason why no one's heard of it,
它肯定来路不正
And it must be a nefarious one.
这意味着除了报警之外
Which means they would do anything
他们会不择手段把它弄回来
outside of going to the cops to get it back.
你或许是对的
You may be right.
警员刚跟沃纳夫妇在特里贝克
So uniforms just talked to the doorman
的看门人谈过话
at the Warners' building in Tribeca.
他说昨天早上霍克去了他们的阁楼  他给开的门
He says he Buzzed Hawke up to their penthouse yesterday morning.
而爱丽丝于昨晚被杀
And Alice was killed last night.
看起来纽约最著名的清道夫
Looks like New York's famous fixer
有点小麻烦了
is in a bit of a fix.
我拜访了我在特里贝克的朋友
So I visited some friends in Tribeca.
这说明不了什么
Doesn't prove anything.
你去沃纳家做什么
Why were you at the Warners'?
我要用他们家浴室
I needed to use their bathroom.
不会又来吧
Are we really gonna dance this dance again?
我还有正事要忙呢
'cause I got better things to do.
给我坐下
Sit down!
赶紧  霍克先生
Now, mr. Hawke.
你休想躲掉这事
You're not walking away from this one.
我从沃纳夫妇那查到你这
I've connected you to the Warners,
又从沃纳夫妇回推到钻石  再回推到被害人
the Warners to the stone, the stone to the dead girl,
查了一圈  又从被害人回推到你头上
and the dead girl back to you.
现在  又有人
And then there is also
持枪攻击两名纽约警局的警探
the matter of the armed assault on two N.Y.P.D. Detectives.
我没杀爱丽丝·克拉克
I did not kill Alice Clark,
那个什么持枪攻击  跟我也没一点关系
and I had nothing to do with any... assault.
那跟谁有关系
Then who did?
把话筒关了再说
Turn off the mic.
干我这行的不得不小心行事
My business is discretion.
所以我说的话都不能记录在案  你明白吗
So none of this is on the record. Do you follow?
没错  的确是沃纳夫妇雇我去找钻石
Yes, the Warners hired me to find the diamond.
但仅此而已
That's it.
那这么说也是你了
So then it was you?
翻她的办公室  她的车
In her office? In the car?
是
Yeah.
但我只是去找钻石
Looking for the stone,
等我到达现场时  爱丽丝已经死了
but Alice was already dead when I got there.
探长  我的确做过
I do things, detective--
见不得人的事  但我从不行凶
questionable things, but I don't kill.
那行
Okay.
那究竟是谁攻击我的同事
So then who attacked my colleagues?
反正不是我
Wasn't me.
也不是沃纳夫妇
Wasn't the Warners.
也许还有其他人在找这块钻石
Maybe somebody else was looking for the diamond.
你又怎么知道是爱丽丝偷的钻石
And how did you know Alice stole it?
因为沃纳夫妇向我描述劫案过程时
Because when the Warners described the mugging,
我就知道是有内鬼接应
I could tell it was an inside job.
沃纳夫妇被劫了
The Warners were mugged?
就在两天前  而且劫匪绝不是临时起意
Two nights ago, and it wasn't random.
劫匪非常清楚什么时候下手  朝哪下手
The mugger knew exactly when and where they were gonna be.
爱丽丝也知道这些
So did Alice.
不仅如此  在一次咨询疗程中
Not only that, but Janet told Alice
珍妮特把钻石保存地点告诉了爱丽丝
about the diamond in one of their sessions.
显然不太可能有别人知道那钻石是真品
Apparently, hardly anyone else knew the diamond was real.
所以我推测爱丽丝肯定身涉其中
I figured Alice had to be involved.
如果沃纳被劫了
Okay, so if the Warners were mugged,
他们为什么不报警
why wouldn't they just go to the police?
他们不想声张
They wanted to keep things quiet.
好
Okay.
我需要你详细说明那次抢劫的具体细节
I need you to tell me everything you know about that mugging.
劫案发生时沃纳夫妇在哪
Where were they when it happened?
他们正从大赦义演现场步行回家
While they were walking home from the amnesty benefit.
爱丽丝是如何作案的
And how did Alice pull it off?
不是她下的手
She didn't.
沃纳夫妇说尽管劫匪戴着滑雪面具
The Warners said the mugger wore a ski mask
但肯定是个男的
but was definitely male.
爱丽丝还有个同伙
Alice had an accomplice?
如果霍克说的是真话
If Hawke's telling the truth,
那就还有其他人涉案
then there's another player involved--
此人知道那钻石是真品
Someone who knew that the diamond was real
于是利用爱丽丝将其抢到手
and used Alice to get it.
你是说爱丽丝身不由己
Do you think Alice was under duress?
被这个同伙强拉下水
That someone was forcing her to help?
威胁要杀了她
Threatening to kill her?
这就能解释她为什么要这么做
That would explain why she did it
以及为什么她想要躲起来
and why she was trying to disappear.
那辆袭警的车有线索了
Hey, we got a hit on our clown car.
巡警发现这辆越野车被遗弃在东河边上
Uniforms found it abandoned by the East River.
车被清洗过  还被一把火烧了
S.U.V.'s been bleached and torched.
鉴定科的人正试着清理收集线索
C.S.U.'s scouring it for clues,
但看起来不那么容易
but seems like it was a high-level job.
另外托瑞那查到了抢劫案的线索
And Tory has something on the mugging.
根据霍克的线索
Okay, now according to Hawke,
当晚11点劫匪在第52街抢走钻石
the mugger snatched the necklace
然后向南朝着第八大道逃窜
at 11 o'clock on 52nd street and bolted south on 8th.
可惜附近没有监控或安保摄像头
Unfortunately, there are no street or security cams in the vicinity,
但是几分钟后有人在第49街和第八大道
but a 9-1-1 call came in two minutes later
交叉口处报警  离案发现场仅3个街区
from 49th and 8th-- 3 blocks away.
这里是接警台  你有什么紧急情况
9-1-1. What's your emergency?
这里有一起肇事逃逸
There's been a hit and run.
您现在在哪
What's your location?
我会派辆救护车过去
I'll send an ambulance.
不是  你没明白
No! You don't understand.
是我肇了事  被撞的人逃逸了
I hit someone, and he ran.
他跑了
He ran?
是的  他穿一身黑衣  戴着个滑雪面具
Yeah, a man dressed all in black, wearing a ski mask.
不知从哪里窜出来的
He came out of nowhere.
肯定就是我们要找的人
That's gotta be our guy.
找到车主
Get over there.
让她详尽描述一下
Get a full description.
我到现在仿佛都能听见他"嘭"的一声
I can still hear the sound of his body
撞在我车前盖上的声音
going "thunk" on my hood.
你还记得他是什么样子吗
Do you remember what he looked like?
不记得  整件事都有点记不清了
No. The whole thing was a blur.
光记得那瘆死人的一声
Just that god-awful sound.
他撞得那么狠  我车前盖上都留了个印子
He hit so hard, he left a dent.
但我下车的时候
But when I got out of my car,
他挣扎着起来  就朝第49街跑了
he just pushed himself off and ran down 49th.
就是这  我演示给你们看
Here. I'll show you.
他的手摁在这里
His hands were up like this,
-然后  -谢谢您
- and then-- - Thank you.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
好  我去叫鉴证组
All right. I'll call C.S.U.
我是莱恩
Ryan here.
你好  警探
Yes, Detective.
我是爱德华·彼得斯
Edward Peters here.
我想我已经对你拿来的钻石有了新结论
I believe I have new insights into your diamond.
我们反复检查了钻石的测试结果
After reviewing test results on the stone,
我和我的同事达成了一致看法
my colleagues and I all reached the same conclusion.
是什么
Which is?
这块钻石完美无瑕
The diamond is flawless--
大自然也造化不出如此完美的钻石
flawless beyond anything nature could create.
你是说那钻石是假的
Oh, you're saying it's fake?
不  它的确是碳结晶而且货真价实
No, it's composed of carbon and entirely real,
只不过是人工制成品
but it is man-made.
人工制成品是什么意思
Whoa. Whoa, whoa, what are you saying, man-made?
工业制钻工艺早已有之
There have long been industrially produced diamonds,
像大自然母亲那样  对碳高温加压
carbon under heat and pressure, mimicking Mother Nature in a lab.
但这样制出的钻石要么很小要么品质低劣
But typically the stones are small or of inferior quality.
也就是说这块钻石不值6000万
So... it's not worth $60 million.
当然不
No.
比6000万多得多
It's actually worth infinitely more.
事实上  它是无价之宝
In fact, it's priceless.
无价之宝
Priceless?
没错  考虑到它的大小和质量
Yeah, apparently, a stone of that size and quality--
可谓是人造钻石的圣杯
it's the holy grail of diamond manufacturing,
这几乎是不可能实现的
considered by most to be impossible.
迄今为止
Until now.
那沃纳夫妇是从哪得来的
So... where did the Warners get it?
又为什么要否认它的存在
And why are they denying its existence?
我不知道
I don't know.
我想我知道是谁想要并袭击了你们
I think I know who wanted it and who attacked you boys.
钻石可以在实验室合成
A diamond like that made in a lab--
这会让钻石公司破产
that would put diamond companies out of business.
你认为是钻石行业派来的小丑
You think it's the diamond industry who sent in the clowns?
考虑到行业的未来
With the future of their industry at stake,
天晓得他们会做出什么事
who knows how far they'd go?
伙计们
Hey, guys.
托瑞有线索
Tory got a hit.
听说鉴证组提取到了一枚指纹
So C.S.U. was able to pull a usable print?
是  我们很幸运  她不太愿意洗车
Yeah, lucky for us, the lady wasn't big into washing her car.
我们扫描指纹时  联邦数据库没有信息
When we ran the print, nothing popped in the federal database.
但考虑到钻石业的国际性
But given the international nature of the diamond industry,
我让托瑞扩大了搜索范围
I asked Tory to cast a wider net.
我们联系了国际刑警
We contacted interpol.
我们的劫匪是外国人
Our mugger's a foreign national?
确切的说是南非人
South African, to be exact.
他的名字叫里奥·维恩加德
His name is Leo Wyngaard--
蹲遍了半数非洲监狱
In and out of half a dozen African prisons.
更别提他还上了恐怖分子名单
Not to mention, he's on the terror watch list.
一看就是钻石集团会雇来干坏事的那种人
Just the kind of guy a diamond cartel would hire for their dirty work.
现在给他们看照片
Now show 'em the picture.
眼熟吧
Look familiar?
他是马特·兰切特
That's Matt Lanchet.
爱丽丝的男朋友
Alice's boyfriend.
我们差点在肯尼迪机场错过他
We almost missed him at J.F.K.
他正准备去约翰内斯堡
He was boarding a flight to Johannesburg.
他一得知我们拿到了钻石就想赶紧抽身
He must have cut his losses once he knew we had secured the diamond.
我还是不明白沃纳夫妇
I still don't get why the Warners
是从哪里得到这么块人造钻石的
had a man-made stone in the first place.
不管是什么原因  里奥想要那钻石
Well, whatever the reason, Leo wanted that diamond,
并且利用爱丽丝得到它
and he was using Alice to get it.
也就是说他强迫她帮忙
Meaning he leveraged her into helping him,
逼她取出钱并订好了飞机
forced her to pull the money out and order up the plane.
然后杀了她
Then he killed her,
把事情弄得像全是她一个人的主意
made this whole thing look like it was her idea.
长官  鉴于这家伙之前为了钻石
Sir, considering that this guy
想把我和埃斯波置于死地
tried to kill me and Espo for that diamond,
能不能让我们进去问个究竟
you mind if we go in there and get some answers?
等等
Wait.
你们以为我是为钻石集团卖命
You think I'm working for the cartels?
是我在利用爱丽丝
That I was using Alice?
我爱爱丽丝
I loved Alice.
你老是用假名字和你爱的女人在一起吗
You always use fake names with women that you love?
她知道我的真实身份
She knew who I really was.
我们是一起干的
We were in this together.
那是当然
Yeah, sure, you were.
你为什么要偷那钻石
Why would you steal that diamond?
我和爱丽丝相遇在卢旺达  当时我在做援助
Alice and I met in Rwanda when I was doing aid work.
我们年轻  我们相爱了
We were young and in love.
有一天  士兵闯进了村子
Then one day, soldiers came to the village,
是钻石集团雇的
financed by the diamond cartel.
我们躲在丛林里亲眼看见他们屠杀了每一个人
We watched from the jungle as they slaughtered everyone--
为了利益争地盘而血流成河
Casualties of a turf war for profit.
那一天改变了我
That day changed me.
我决心要用毕生阻止钻石集团的血腥行径
I dedicated myself to stopping the cartels' bloody practices.
我知道不能让爱丽丝卷入这种生活
It was a life I knew Alice couldn't be a part of,
但我从没停止过爱她
but I never stopped loving her.
所以你偷了一颗人造钻石
So you're working against the cartels
这就是你对付钻石集团的办法
by stealing a man-made diamond?
两年前  钻石开始出现在
Two years ago, stones started popping up
欧洲和中东市场
in Europe and the Middle East--
由于完美无缺  卖出了数百万的价钱
Flawless, being sold for millions.
这时我的一个宝石专家朋友偶然得到了两颗
That's when a gemologist friend of mine happened across a pair of them.
他发现它们是完全相同的
He discovered that they were exactly the same.
大自然决不会造出完全相同的两件物品
Nature doesn't make exact copies.
它们是人造的
They were man-made.
没错  我试着追踪它们的来源
Yeah. I tried to trace them back to their source.
但我只知道它们来自美国
All I knew was that they were coming out of The States,
这时爱丽丝突然联系了我
and then Alice called me out of the blue,
说她的一个客户  史蒂夫·沃纳有个秘密
said one of her clients, Steve Warner, had a secret.
等等  你是要告诉我史蒂夫·沃纳能做钻石
Wait. Are you telling me that Steve Warner can make diamonds?
没错
Yes.
人造钻石并不稀奇
Man-made diamonds are nothing new,
但之前没人能做出那个质量
but no one had ever produced this quality of gem before--
大而没有瑕疵
big and flawless.
钻石开采很快就会成为历史
Soon, diamond mines would be a relic of the past.
史蒂夫·沃纳的技术能改变一切
Steve Warner's technology could change everything.
于是我联系到了沃纳本人
So I approached Warner.
我请求他能把他的技术公开
I begged him to make his technology available,
但他否认他拥有这项技术
but he denied he even had it.
这技术只是用来让他中饱私囊
He was just using it to line his own pockets.
我们要让世人知道  我们需要证据
The world needed to know, and we needed proof.
那条项链就是证据
The necklace.
我们知道如果我们能检查一下那块钻石
We knew that if we could just examine that stone,
我们就能把它和其他两个联系在一起
that we could tie it back to the others,
我们就能向所有人揭露他们的行径
then we could show everyone what it was doing,
人们能亲眼看到人造钻石是有可能的
and they could all see that it was possible.
每个人终能打开贸易壁垒
Then... everyone would eventually unlock the code.
顷刻间  完美无瑕的人造钻石
Then all of a sudden, flawless, man-made diamonds
涌入市场
would flood the market.
没有钻石集团  就没有流血事件
No more cartels. No more sponsored bloodshed.
我们就能改变世界
We were gonna change the world.
那晚爱丽丝订了一架飞机带我们去一个私人实验室
That night, alice had a plane standing by to take us to a private lab.
但她没有出现
But she never showed.
还有没有谁知道你们要拿走钻石
Did anyone else know you'd taken the diamond?
知道钻石丢失的人就只有
The only people that knew that diamond was gone
我  爱丽丝和沃纳夫妇
were me, Alice, and the Warners.
我们说过  我们不会回答关于钻石的任何问题
We told you, we're not answering questions about that diamond.
行  没问题
Yeah, that's okay.
你们也说不出什么我们不知道的事情了
There's nothing that you can say that we don't already know.
比如  我们知道那是人造的
For instance, we know it's man-made.
我们也知道制造钻石的人就是你
And we know you are the man who made it.
我们还知道
We also know that...
背地里将这些人造钻石
You made a lot of cash secretly selling
贩卖到海外让你赚了不少现款
those man-made diamonds on foreign markets.
太荒谬了
That's ridiculous.
你知道我身价有多少吗
Do you know what I'm worth?
我为什么要干那种勾当
Why would I do that?
经济危机的时候你收到了沉重打击
You took a huge hit during the economic downturn.
你当时向各方欠下巨债
You were leveraged to the hilt.
你需要大量现款
You needed that cash.
就算你说的是真的
Even if what you're saying is true,
也不代表是我杀了爱丽丝
that doesn't mean I murdered Alice!
但你的确雇了霍克去找回钻石
You did hire Hawke to get that diamond back.
好吧
Okay.
我也是别无他法了
I had to.
我怕范·勒恩发现我的生意
I was afraid Von Roenn would find out.
范·勒恩  那个钻石集团头目
VonRoenn, the diamond cartel?
他们跟这事有什么关系
What do they have to do with this?
我还在工程学院的时候
When I was in engineering school,
发明了在实验室制造钻石的方法
I developed a process for lab-grown diamonds.
但当时的成品又小又有瑕疵
But all I could manage were small flawed stones.
一点也不值钱
They were worthless.
那是我身无分文  所以把这项技术卖给了
At the time I had no money, so I sold the technology
唯一对它感兴趣的人  范·勒恩
to the only people interested-- VonRoenn.
他们想打压竞争对手
They wanted to stifle the competition.
保护自己的市场份额
You know, protect their market share.
几年前  我与珍妮特的关系遇到瓶颈
Then a few years ago, Janet and I hit a rough patch.
我想送她点有意义的东西
And I wanted to give her something meaningful.
要买一颗钻石太容易了
It was too easy just to buy her a diamond.
所以我觉得自己做一颗
So you decided to make one of your own.
我找出我的实验设备
I broke out my equipment
以便给她做颗小钻石
so I could make her a small diamond.
但在制作过程中
But in the process,
我取得了惊人的突破
I had a game-changing breakthrough.
我的小浪漫
My little romantic gesture
造就了史上最大颗的钻石之一
became one of the biggest diamonds in history.
忽然间  我能够制作完美的钻石了
Suddenly, I could make flawless stones...
想做多少就多少
As many as I wanted.
这项技术现在是属于范·勒恩
With technology that now belong to VonRoenn.
经济危机的时候你们需要大量现金
And when the downturn hit and you needed cash...
意识到只要不被发现  这是再好不过的生财之道
You realized you had the means as long as no one knew.
但它违反了我们的协议
It violated our agreement.
如果范·勒恩发现这事  他们会毁了我
If Von Roenn found out, they'd ruin me.
这也是你雇佣突袭队
Which is why you hired a strike team
要从我们手里抢回钻石的原因
to recover that stone from our custody.
什么  我不知道你们在说什么
What? I don't know what you're talking about.
沃纳先生  我们找到了突袭队乘坐的车子
Mr. Warner, we found the SUV they used.
它已经被烧毁
It had been torched.
但鉴证组把汽车识别码恢复了
But CSU Still was able to pull the VIN number.
结果显示  车是在皇后区的车库里被偷的
Turns out it was stolen from a garage in Queens.
车库的所有人约瑟夫·比安奇先生
And the garage owner, Joseph Bianchi?
他是你保安主管的连襟
He's the brother-in-law of your head of security.
我们还查到通联纪录
We also pulled phone records
发现你和他曾在
and found that you and he had exchanged
袭击发生前的一小时之内通话至少六次
at least half a dozen phone calls in the hours before the attack.
什么
What?
你对袭击下达了指令
You ordered that strike.
我没打过那些电话
I-I didn't make these calls.
我当时根本不在家
I-I wasn't even home.
这是...
It's--I--
不
No.
珍妮特
Janet?
你做了什么
What did you do?
我做了什么
What did I do?
我当她是自家人
I treated her like family.
信任她
I trusted her.
当霍克查出是爱丽丝偷了钻石  我去见她
When Hawke found out it was Alice, I went to her,
求她把钻石还给我
begging for her to give the stone back.
我只是想吓吓她
I only meant to scare her,
但她对我举起枪
But she grabbed for the gun and...
她可能会暴露我们的生意  史蒂夫
she would've exposed us, Steve.
那样我们就什么都没有了
We were going to lose everything.
我必须阻止她
I had to stop her. I had to get it back...
为了我们
For us.
为了你
For you.
不准睁眼哦
Keep 'em closed.
卡塞尔  我发誓  你要是把我送到莱纳斯面前
Castle, I swear if you're bringing me face-to-face with Linus,
我会拿枪射它
I'm gonna pull my gun out and shoot him.
没那个必要
That will not be necessary.
好吧
Okay.
好了  睁开吧
Okay, open.
贝壳
Seashells?
不仅仅是贝壳
Well, not just seashells.
这些是我们的贝壳
Those are our seashells.
是我们第一次一起在
We collected those--
汉普顿散步的时候捡的
On our first walk in the hamptons.
卡塞尔  你把它们都留下啦
Castle, you kept these?
我知道它们摆在这里有点不搭
Now, I know it doesn't really go with the space
但至少它们在早晨不会流着口水盯着你
but at least it won't be hungrily staring at you in the morning.
你不用为我做这些的
You didn't have to do this.
不  我应该的  我刚读完爱丽丝的书
No, I did. I did. I finished reading Alice's book,
其中有一章是写给我们这类伴侣的
and there's a chapter in there that speaks to couples like us.
我俩都是主导型人格
See, we're both alphas.
书上说  我们得一起给共同的生活空间下定义
And it says that we need to define our shared territory together.
这些艺术品  讲述的都是我的故事
These art pieces all over-- these are all my stories.
但这些贝壳  讲的是我们的
But the shells? That's ours.
我喜欢我们的故事
I like our story.
我也是
Yeah, me, too.
这下糟了
That can't be good.
你得承认  这是我们自找的
You have to admit that we brought this upon ourselves.
真的假的
Seriously?
如果你害怕
Look, if you're scared,
今晚可以跟我一起挤挤
you can always sleep on my side of the bed tonight.
成交
Deal.